Guide to the Communications Workers of America, Local 1250 Records WAG.258
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, Local 1250 Records
1961-2000
1970-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America. Local 1250
Algiere, Mary Lou
WAG.258
1.25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 folder.
Communications Workers of America, Local 1250 represented AT&T Long Lines employees in Connecticut. The Local was active from the early 1960s until 2000, when its membership was absorbed by CWA Local 1153 based in Westchester, NY. The collection consists of minutes of Executive Board and General Membership meetings, bargaining files, grievance records, reports, correspondence, and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mary Lou Algiere, 2005. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2005.013, 2005.014 and NPA.2006.065.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Communications Workers of America (CWA), Local 1250 represented AT&T Long Lines employees in Connecticut. The Local was active from the early 1960s until 2000, when its membership was absorbed by CWA Local 1153, based in Westchester, NY. Among the officers represented in the records are Richard G. Winsch, local president in the early years; John Trainer, vice-president and later president; Robert H. Damrau, secretary, later vice-president and president; Martin Niatopsky, vice-president and later president; William Flagg, secretary; and William L. Sharkey, president. The Local took an active role in meetings and conferences of CWA District 1, the CWA's Communications and Technology and Long Lines Divisions, and regional and statewide common-interest forums. Among the issues of concern to the Local, reflected in the very frank local presidents' reports, are the post-Divestiture transfer of AT&T employees, the impact of new technologies, the role of Long Lines workers within the larger structure of the CWA, bargaining tactics, quality control and speed-up on the job.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of minutes of Executive Board and General Membership meetings from 1966-2000, and bargaining files, grievance records, organizing records, membership reports, reports by Local 1250's President, correspondence, and photographs, dating from 1961-2000.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, Local 1151 Records (WAG 244)
Communications Workers of America Records (WAG 124)
Communications Workers of America Records: Addendum (WAG 124.1)
Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Records (WAG 59)
Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 Records (WAG 132)
Communications Workers of America, District 1 Records (WAG 117)
Arrangement
The records are arranged in three series. The contents of each series are arranged alphabetically. The series arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series 1, Minutes, 1966-2000
Series II, Subject Files, 1961-2000
Series III, Photographs 1981-1995, undated
Telecommunication -- Employees -- United States.; Correspondence.; Labor unions -- Contract administration.; Labor unions -- Telecommunication -- United States.; Photographs.; Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States.; Reports.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company -- Employees.; Labor unions -- Officials and employees.; Collective labor agreements -- Telecommunication.; Minutes (administrative records); Transcripts.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company; Algiere, Mary Lou
- Series I: Minutes, 1966-2000
  Scope and Content Note
  Series consists of the minutes of Executive Board and General Membership meetings.
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1979-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1980-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1961-2000
  Series consists of a variety of materials related to the activities of the Local, including bargaining records, correspondence of the Local headquarters, organizing records, membership reports, and reports by the Local president.
  - Bargaining, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bargaining, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bargaining, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bargaining, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Local Headquarters, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - External Organizing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Grievances, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Grievances, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Local Dinner-Dance, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Membership Development Reports, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - President's Reports, 1981-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Wage/Zone Increase, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Certificates, 1957-1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series III: Photographs, 1981-1995, undated
  Series consists of 16 black-and-white and color glossy photographs, mostly 8x10, including group portraits from conferences and other gatherings in the early-1980s and 1995, and black-and-white documentary photographs of CWA workers on strike, including portraits of workers with strike signs that read, "CWA on Strike Against The Bell System," and photographs of union meetings.
  - CWA Local 1250 Photos, 1981-1995, undated (Box A004)